<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io</id>
    <title>拉克希米-Laxmi</title>
    <updated>2020-02-14T14:44:18.814Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>我们必须有勇气面对严峻的现实。
We must have the courage to face the bitter truth.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2020, 拉克希米-Laxmi</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[《我的英雄学院》被抵制]]></title>
        <id>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/WmA_vUSjn</id>
        <link href="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/WmA_vUSjn">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-02-14T12:15:03.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>以下引用自<a href="https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E9%9B%84%E5%AD%A6%E9%99%A2/15421219">百度百科</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>在2月3日发售的《周刊少年JUMP》2020年10号上，该漫画259话中，作者将一个做人体实验的反派命名为志贺丸太，并给丸太标注读音maruta。“志贺”取自日本细菌学家志贺洁，也被用作“志贺杆菌”的命名。“志贺杆菌”又被称为“痢疾杆菌”，曾被用于“七三一”部队的人体实验。丸木(maruta)在日语中意为圆木，引申意思为“试验品”，是侵华日军“七三一”细菌部队对那些被迫接受人体实验的受害者的污辱性称呼。<br>
漫画发布仅一天，该作品哔哩哔哩评分就下降至2.3分（最低2.0分）。随后，日本出版方集英社发布声明称此为“无心之失”，并未致歉，这使网友更加愤怒。2月7日，原作者堀越耕平才与集英社联合发文道歉，并承诺更换名称。对此，不少读者观众怒批：“毫无诚意！”并采取了不同方式进行抵制。</p>
<img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581684310727.jpg" height="120" width="76" />
<blockquote>
<p>图片来自<a href="https://baike.baidu.com/pic/%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E9%9B%84%E5%AD%A6%E9%99%A2/15421219/0/a50f4bfbfbedab6470460a94f836afc379311ea9">百度百科</a></p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>以下为作者在推特上发布的道歉内容<br>
为《我的英雄学术界》(2020年第10期)上的表述表示道歉</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在《周刊少年JUMP》2020年第10期（2月3日出版）的《我的英雄学院》第259集中，许多中外读者指出，这个人物的名字“志賀丸太”（しがまるた/Shiga maruta）是对过去悲惨历史的回忆。“志贺”（Shiga）是根据其他角色的名字命名的，而“丸太”（Maruta）是根据角色的外观命名的，并没有打算与过去的历史有交集。然而，这个名字和“邪恶组织博士”这一人物的设定的组合，令海外读者，尤其是中国读者感到不快。编辑部应该事先对这个表述做一个彻底的检查。深深道歉。我们把这个问题当作一个严重的警示，并将在电子版漫画转为纸质版前，迅速更改这个名字。为了防止这种情况在未来发生，我们将理解不同的历史和文化，继续努力提升我们的漫画。我们将在照顾大众感受的同时，继续提供受大家喜爱的漫画。</p>
<p>2020年2月7日集英社</p>
<p>我在《我的英雄学院》第259集画的“志賀丸太”（しがまるた）让很多人感到很不舒服，实在对不起。“志贺”对前“敌联合”的首领“All For One”（オール・フォー・ワン）痴迷，想接近他的存在。而“All For One”的本名“死柄木（レがらき）”的一部分被称为“志贺（しが）”，而“丸太”（圆木）则意在表达“胖乎乎”（丸々と太った）的感觉。两者都是偶然的，无意伤害读者。我真诚地道歉。在未来，我们将尽一切努力不重复这样的事情。</p>
<p>堀越耕平</p>
<blockquote>
<p>以下为作者在推特上发布的道歉内容（原文）<br>
「週刊少年ジャンプ」2020年10号「僕のヒーローアカデミア 』における表現についてのお詫び</p>
</blockquote>
<p>「週刊少年ジャンプ』 2020年10号（2月3日発売）掲載の「僕のヒーローアカデミア 』第259話に登場したキャラクター名「志賀丸太（しがまるた）」について、過去の悲惨な歴史の記憶を想起させるとのご指摘を、中国をはじめとする海外の読者の方々から多くいただきました。「志質（しが）」は他の登場人物名の一部から、「丸太（まるた）」はその外見から命名したもので、過去の歴史と重ね合わせる意図は全くありませんでした。しかしながら、「悪の組織の医師」というキャラクターの設定とこれらの名前が合わさった結果、中国をはじめとする海外の読者の皆様に不快な思いをさせてしまいました。事前に編集部が表現について十全な検討を行うべきでした。深くお詫び申し上げます。今回の問題を真撃に受け止め、当該キャラクター名を、紙版においてはコミックス収録時に、電子版においてはすみやかに変更いたします今後、このような事態を起こさないよう、様々な歴史と文化への理解を深める努力を続けるとともに、多くの人々の気持ちに寄り添いながら、皆様に愛きれる漫画をお届けしてまいります。</p>
<p>2020年2月7日株式会社集英社</p>
<p>「僕のヒーローアカデミア」第259話で描いた「志賀丸太」という名前について、大勢の方に大変不快な思いをさせてしまい、誠に申し訳ございません。「志賀（しが）」は、彼がかつての「敵連合（ヴィラン連合）」のボス「オール・フォー・ワン」に心酔し、自らその存在に近づきたいと思ったことから、その本名「死柄木（レがらき）」の一部をとって「志質（しが）」と名乗ることにしたもので、「丸太」は「丸々と太った」感じを表せればと名付けたものです。いずれも偶然で、読者のみなさんを傷つける意図は全くありませんでした。心からお詫びいたします。今後、二度とこのようなことを繰り返さぬよう、努めてまいります。</p>
<p>堀越耕平</p>
<td>
<a><img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581689630397.jpg"></a>
</td>
<td>
<a><img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581689649626.jpg"></a>
</td>
<td>
<a><img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581681665572.jpg"></a>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Hero Academia boycotted in China]]></title>
        <id>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/Vq1VuZyZQ</id>
        <link href="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/Vq1VuZyZQ">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-02-14T11:31:19.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>From <a href="https://bokunoheroacademia.fandom.com/wiki/My_Hero_Academia_Wiki">fandom.com</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>My Hero Academia (僕のヒーローアカデミア Boku no Hīrō Akademia?) is a Manga series serialized by Shonen Jump and written by Kohei Horikoshi. The series has been adapted into an Anime series and an Anime Movie, as well as spawning the Spinoff series My Hero Academia Vigilantes.</p>
<p>The story is set in the modern-day, except people with special powers called &quot;Quirks&quot; have become commonplace throughout the world. In a world of chaos and confusion, Pro Heroes have now risen as the new profession to fight off powerful super villains.<br>
<img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581684310727.jpg" height="120" width="76" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Photo from <a href="https://baike.baidu.com/pic/%E6%88%91%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E9%9B%84%E5%AD%A6%E9%99%A2/15421219/0/a50f4bfbfbedab6470460a94f836afc379311ea9">baidu</a></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Event describtion Form baike.baidu.com<br>
<em>Translated by Google</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>On &quot;Weekly Boys JUMP&quot; released on February 3, 2020, in the comic 259 words, the author named a villain doing human experiments as Shiga Maruta, and gave Maruta the pronunciation. &quot;Shiga&quot; was taken from Japanese bacteriologist Shiga Jie and is also used as the name for &quot;Shiga bacillus&quot;. &quot;Shigella&quot; is also known as &quot;dysentery bacillus&quot; and has been used in human experiments on the &quot;July 31&quot; unit. Maruta in Japanese means roundwood, which means &quot;test product&quot;, and it is an insulting name for the victims of the &quot;July Trinity&quot; bacterial unit of the Japanese invaders who were forced to undergo human experiments.<br>
Only one day after the comic was released, the Bilibili score of the work dropped to 2.3 (minimum 2.0). Subsequently, the Japanese publisher Shueisha issued a statement calling this an &quot;unintentional mistake&quot; without apologizing, which made netizens even more angry. On February 7th, the original author Ying Yue Gengping and Jiyingsha jointly issued an apology and promised to change the name. In response, many readers criticized: &quot;No sincerity!&quot; And adopted different methods to resist.</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>Apology from author's twitter<br>
Apology for expression in &quot;Weekly Shonen Jump&quot; 2020 No. 10 &quot;My Hero Academia&quot; <em>Translated by Google</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Appeared in &quot;My Hero Academia&quot; episode 259 published in &quot;Weekly Shonen Jump&quot; 2020 No. 10 (released on February 3)  Many readers from China and abroad have pointed out that the character name &quot;Shigamaruta&quot; is reminiscent of memories of the tragic history of the past.  &quot;Shiga&quot; was named after some of the other characters, and &quot;Maruta&quot; was named after its appearance, with no intent to overlap with past history.  However, the combination of these characters and the setting of the character &quot;Doctor of evil organization&quot; has been annoying to readers overseas, especially in China.  The editorial department should have done a thorough examination of the expression in advance.  Deeply apologize.  Taking this issue as a serious hit, the character name will be changed promptly in the electronic version when recording comics in the paper version, and in order to prevent such a situation from happening in the future, understanding various history and culture  We will continue to strive to deepen our manga, and we will continue to deliver cartoons that can be loved by everyone while snuggling with the feelings of many people.</p>
<p>February 7, 2020 Shueisha Co., Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;My Hero Academia&quot; The name &quot;Shiga log&quot; that I drew in episode 259 made many people feel very uncomfortable, sorry.  &quot;Shiga&quot; became enthusiastic about the former &quot;All For One&quot; boss of the &quot;Enemy Coalition (Villan Coalition)&quot;, and his real name &quot;Death&quot;  A part of the pattern is called &quot;Shiga,&quot; and &quot;log&quot; is intended to express the feeling of &quot;chubby and fat.&quot;  Both were accidental and had no intent to hurt the readers.  I sincerely apologize.  In the future, we will make every effort not to repeat such a thing.</p>
<p>Kohei Horikoshi</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Apology from author's twitter (original language)<br>
「週刊少年ジャンプ」2020年10号「僕のヒーローアカデミア 』における表現についてのお詫び</p>
</blockquote>
<p>「週刊少年ジャンプ』 2020年10号（2月3日発売）掲載の「僕のヒーローアカデミア 』第259話に登場したキャラクター名「志賀丸太（しがまるた）」について、過去の悲惨な歴史の記憶を想起させるとのご指摘を、中国をはじめとする海外の読者の方々から多くいただきました。「志質（しが）」は他の登場人物名の一部から、「丸太（まるた）」はその外見から命名したもので、過去の歴史と重ね合わせる意図は全くありませんでした。しかしながら、「悪の組織の医師」というキャラクターの設定とこれらの名前が合わさった結果、中国をはじめとする海外の読者の皆様に不快な思いをさせてしまいました。事前に編集部が表現について十全な検討を行うべきでした。深くお詫び申し上げます。今回の問題を真撃に受け止め、当該キャラクター名を、紙版においてはコミックス収録時に、電子版においてはすみやかに変更いたします今後、このような事態を起こさないよう、様々な歴史と文化への理解を深める努力を続けるとともに、多くの人々の気持ちに寄り添いながら、皆様に愛きれる漫画をお届けしてまいります。</p>
<p>2020年2月7日株式会社集英社</p>
<p>「僕のヒーローアカデミア」第259話で描いた「志賀丸太」という名前について、大勢の方に大変不快な思いをさせてしまい、誠に申し訳ございません。「志賀（しが）」は、彼がかつての「敵連合（ヴィラン連合）」のボス「オール・フォー・ワン」に心酔し、自らその存在に近づきたいと思ったことから、その本名「死柄木（レがらき）」の一部をとって「志質（しが）」と名乗ることにしたもので、「丸太」は「丸々と太った」感じを表せればと名付けたものです。いずれも偶然で、読者のみなさんを傷つける意図は全くありませんでした。心からお詫びいたします。今後、二度とこのようなことを繰り返さぬよう、努めてまいります。</p>
<p>堀越耕平</p>
<table>
<tr>
<td>
<a><img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581689630397.jpg"></a>
</td>
<td>
<a><img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581689649626.jpg"></a>
</td>
<td>
<a><img src="https://laxmi-blog.github.io/post-images/1581681665572.jpg"></a>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[关于]]></title>
        <id>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/about-cn</id>
        <link href="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/about-cn">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-31T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>欢迎来到拉克希米的博客🤝</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>欢迎来到拉克希米的博客🤝</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<img src="file://C:/MyFiles/MyNextCloud/MyBlog/GrideaData/post-images/1579357064656.jpg" alt="链接的手" width="200" height="200" loading="lazy">
<p>Photo by <a href="/photographer/juliaf-55850">Julia Freeman-Woolpert</a> from <a href="https://freeimages.com/">FreeImages</a></p>
<h1 id="关于本站">关于本站</h1>
<ul>
<li>这是一个由匿名作者们合力撰写的双语博客，主要面向中国大部分能使用互联网的读者，同时也希望能为外国友人提供了解中国的渠道。</li>
<li>为了便于各方的阅读，英文版博文(博客的文章）的内容会与中文版有些微不同。</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2">百度百科 博客</a><br>
博客，仅音译，英文名为Blogger，为Web Log的混成词。它的正式名称为网络日记；又音译为部落格或部落阁等，是使用特定的软件，在网络上出版、发表和张贴个人文章的人，或者是一种通常由个人管理、不定期张贴新的文章的网站。</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="博主是谁">博主是谁</h1>
<p>博主是所有自愿无偿供稿的投稿者。我们共用一个笔名：拉克希米（Laxmi）。</p>
<h1 id="欢迎来稿">欢迎来稿</h1>
<p>邮箱：<a href="mailto:Laxmi_Hyacintha@protonmail.com">Laxmi_Hyacintha@protonmail.com</a><br>
<em>为保证邮件安全，推荐国内读者使用<a href="https://mail.protonmail.com/login">Protonmail</a>邮箱与管理员联系</em></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[About]]></title>
        <id>https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/about-en</id>
        <link href="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post/about-en">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-31T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Welcome to Laxmi's blog.🤝</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Welcome to Laxmi's blog.🤝</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://Laxmi-Blog.github.io/post-images/1579357064656.jpg" alt="Linked Hands" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Photo by <a href="/photographer/juliaf-55850">Julia Freeman-Woolpert</a> from <a href="https://freeimages.com/">FreeImages</a></p>
<h1 id="about-our-website">About our website</h1>
<ul>
<li>This is a bilingual blog written by anonymous authors. It is mainly aimed at readers who can use the Internet in China. It also hopes to provide foreign friends with a channel to understand China.</li>
<li>For the convenience of all parties, the content of the English version of the blog post will be slightly different from the Chinese version.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="whos-blogger">Who's blogger</h1>
<p>The bloggers are contributors to all voluntary unpaid contributions. We share a pseudonym: Laxmi.</p>
<h1 id="contributions-welcome">Contributions welcome</h1>
<p>Email: <a href="mailto:Laxmi_Hyacintha@protonmail.com">Laxmi_Hyacintha@protonmail.com</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>